<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Paran.Blue</title>
    <link>https://bynaki.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Paran.Blue</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://bynaki.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 12:54:59 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bynaki.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Js :: Promise.all()</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/js.promise-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 12:54:59 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/js.promise-all/</guid>
      <description>Promise.all() source:
const times = [2000, 500, 3000, 1000] await Promise.all(times.map(async t =&amp;gt; { await stop(t) console.log(t) })) output:
500 1000 2000 3000 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node :: Usage nvm</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.usage-nvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:51:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.usage-nvm/</guid>
      <description>Usage NVM To download, compile, and install the latest release of node, do this:
nvm install node # &amp;#34;node&amp;#34; is an alias for the latest version To install a specific version of node:
nvm install 6.14.4 # or 10.10.0, 8.9.1, etc The first version installed becomes the default. New shells will start with the default version of node (e.g., nvm alias default).
You can list available versions using ls-remote:
nvm ls-remote And then in any new shell just use the installed version:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Js :: Generator</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/js.generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 01:18:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/js.generator/</guid>
      <description>Generator **Generator** 객체는 generator function 으로부터 반환된 값이며 반복자와 반복자 프로토콜을 준수합니다.
문법 function* gen() { yield 1; yield 2; yield 3; } var g = gen(); // &amp;#34;Generator { }&amp;#34; 메서드   Generator.prototype.next()
yield 표현을 통해 yield된 값을 반환합니다.
  Generator.prototype.return()
주어진 값을 반환하고 생성기를 종료합니다.
  Generator.prototype.throw()
생성기로 에러를 throw합니다.
  예시 무한 반복자 function* idMaker(){ var index = 0; while(true) yield index++; } var gen = idMaker(); // &amp;#34;Generator { }&amp;#34;  console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node :: Deleting Data in SQLite Database from a Node.js Application</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.delete-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 20:19:44 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.delete-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>Summary: in this tutorial, you will learn how to delete data in the SQLite database from a Node.js application.
To delete data in the SQLite database from a Node.js application, you use the following steps:
 Open a database connection. Execute a DELETE statement. Close the database connection.  For the demonstration, we will use the langs table in the sample.db database that we created in the previous tutorial.
Deleting data example To delete data from a table, you use the DELETE statement as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node :: Updating Data in SQLite Database from a Node.js Application</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.update-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 16:25:41 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.update-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>Summary: this tutorial shows you how to update data in the SQLite database from a Node.js application.
To update data in the SQLite database from a Node.js application, you use these steps:
 Open a database connection. Execute an UPDATE statement. Close the database connection.  For the demonstration, we will use the langs table in the sample.db database that we created in the previous tutorial.
Updating data example To update data in a table, you use the UPDATE statement as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node :: Inserting Data Into an SQLite Table from a Node.js Application</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.insert-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:15:38 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.insert-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>Summary: in this tutorial, you will learn how to insert one or more row into an SQLite table from a Node.js application.
To insert data into an SQLite table from a Node.js application, you follow these steps:
 Open a database connection. Execute an INSERT statement. Close the database connection.  For the demonstration, we will create a new database named sample.db in the db folder.
When you open a database connection in the default mode, the database is created if it does not exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node :: Controlling the Execution Flow of Statements</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.controlling-flow-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 01:22:48 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.controlling-flow-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>Summary: in this tutorial, you will learn how to control the execution flow of statements.
The sqlite3 module provides you with two methods for controlling the execution flow of statements. The serialize() method allows you to execute statements in serialized mode, while the parallelize() method executes the statements in parallel.
Let’s look into each method in detail to understand how it works.
Executing statement in serialized mode with Database.serialize The serialize() method puts the execution mode into serialized mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node :: Querying Data in SQLite Database from Node.js Applications</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.querying-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:21:52 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.querying-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>Summary: in this tutorial, you will learn how to query data from the SQLite database from a Node.js application using sqlite3 API.
To query data in SQLite database from a Node.js application, you use these steps:
 Open a database connection. Execute a SELECT statement and process the result set. Close the database connection.  The sqlite3 module provides you with some methods for querying data such as all(), each() and get().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node :: Connecting To SQLite Database Using Node.js</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.connecting-sqlite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:31:40 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.connecting-sqlite/</guid>
      <description>Summary: in this tutorial, you will learn how to connect to an SQLite database from Node.js applications.
Installing sqlite3 module To interact with the SQLite database, you need to download and install sqlite3 module. You can use npm to do so using the following command:
&amp;gt; npm install sqlite3 After installing the sqlite3 module, you are ready to connect to a SQLite database from a Node.js application.
@types도 같이 깔자.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS :: How to deploy GitHub pages with AWS Route 53 registered custom domain and force HTTPS</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/aws.route53-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 23:35:55 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/aws.route53-github/</guid>
      <description>In this guide I will explain how to deploy a website to GitHub pages forcing HTTPS over a custom domain that is registered with AWS Route 53. We will set up our domain so that the www subdomain will redirect to the apex domain.
Summary  Set up the GitHub repo Commit and push an index.html or use Jekyll Configure AWS Route 53  Step 1: Create GitHub repo and turn on GitHub Pages  If it does not exist yet, create a repository using the naming pattern your-github-username.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac :: Take a screenshot on your Mac</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/mac.screenshot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 23:01:41 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/mac.screenshot/</guid>
      <description>You can capture the entire screen, a window, or just a portion of the screen.
How to take a screenshot on your Mac  To take a screenshot, press and hold these three keys together: Shift, Command, and 3. If you see a thumbnail in the corner of your screen, click it to edit the screenshot. Or wait for the screenshot to save to your desktop.  How to capture a portion of the screen  Press and hold these three keys together: Shift, Command, and 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node :: Upgrading npm</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.upgrading-npm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:34:28 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/node.upgrading-npm/</guid>
      <description>Is there a quicker way of just updating all the dependencies, including major version changes? So, like npm update but for major version updates as well?
Yes, there is a tool called npm-check-updates that will do this. Just run the following command:
npx npm-check-updates -u This will update the dependencies to the latest versions (including major version changes) in the package.json file. If we are happy to go ahead with the upgrades we need to run the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git :: Default Branch를 &#39;master&#39;에서 &#39;main&#39;으로 변경</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/git.default-branch-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 01:47:32 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/git.default-branch-main/</guid>
      <description>오래된 프로젝트의 기본 branch 이름이 master라면 main으로 변경하자.
github 에서 Settings &amp;gt; Branches &amp;gt; Default branch 에서 master 를 main 으로 변경한 후 로컬에서 다음을 실행한다.
git branch -m master main git fetch origin git branch -u origin/main main git remote set-head origin -a git int 할때 기본 branch를 main으로 하기 위한 config 설정.
$ git config --global init.defaultBranch main </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS :: Web Font (@font-face)</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/css.font-face/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 23:38:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/css.font-face/</guid>
      <description>웹 폰트 또한 font-family 속성을 사용하지만, @font-face 지시어(directive)라는 CSS 명령어를 사용해서 웹 브라우저에게 해당 서체를 다운로드할 것을 알리면서 사용할 수 있습니다.
웹 폰트를 위해 사용하는 CSS 코드는 매우 간단하며, 두 개의 CSS 명령어만이 필요합니다.
 @font-face 지시어는 웹 브라우저에게 서체 이름과 다운받을 위치를 알려줍니다. 이 명령어의 동작 방식은 뒤에서 살펴봅니다. font-family 속성의 사용법은 위에서 언급한 일반 폰트의 사용법과 같습니다. 일단 @font-face 를 사용해 브라우저에게 서체를 다운받으라 알린 다음에는, 어느 CSS에서도 일반 폰트와 동일하게 font-family를 통해 사용할 수 있게 됩니다.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hammerspoon</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/hammerspoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 19:52:16 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/hammerspoon/</guid>
      <description>hammerspoon은 macOS에서만 돌아가는 자동화 툴이다. Lua를 내장하고 있다. 마음에 든다.  What is Hammerspoon? This is a tool for powerful automation of OS X. At its core, Hammerspoon is just a bridge between the operating system and a Lua scripting engine.
What gives Hammerspoon its power is a set of extensions that expose specific pieces of system functionality, to the user. With these, you can write Lua scripts to control many aspects of your OS X environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo :: Quick Start</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/hugo.quick-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 23:25:02 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/hugo.quick-start/</guid>
      <description>Create a Hugo site using the beautiful Ananke theme.
 This quick start uses macOS in the examples. For instructions about how to install Hugo on other operating systems, see install.
It is recommended to have Git installed to run this tutorial.
For other approaches learning Hugo like book or a video tutorial refer to the external learning resources page.
 Step 1: Install Hugo  Homebrew and MacPorts, package managers for macOS, can be installed from brew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown :: Syntax</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/markdown.syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 22:58:56 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/markdown.syntax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git :: Submodule</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/git.submodule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 22:02:06 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/git.submodule/</guid>
      <description>About submodule.
Add Submodule 서브모듈 추가 하기
$ git submodule add https://github.com/chaconinc/DbConnector 기본적으로 서브모듈은 프로젝트 저장소의 이름으로 디렉토리를 만든다. 예제에서는 DbConnector라는 이름으로 만든다. 명령의 마지막에 원하는 이름을 넣어 다른 디렉토리 이름으로 서브모듈을 추가할 수도 있다. 우선 .gitmodules 파일이 만들어졌다. 이 파일은 서브디렉토리와 하위 프로젝트 URL의 매핑 정보를 담은 설정파일이다.
[submodule &amp;quot;DbConnector&amp;quot;] path = DbConnector url = https://github.com/chaconinc/DbConnector Submodule 포함한 프로젝트 Clone 서브모듈을 포함하는 프로젝트를 Clone 하는 예제를 살펴본다. 이런 프로젝트를 Clone 하면 기본적으로 서브모듈 디렉토리는 빈 디렉토리이다.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ava :: Debugging tests with Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/ava.debugging-vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 17:32:43 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bynaki.github.io/posts/ava.debugging-vscode/</guid>
      <description>Debugging tests with Visual Studio Code
You can debug your tests using Visual Studio Code.
Debugging with the debug terminal You can use VS Code&amp;rsquo;s “JavaScript Debug Terminal” to automatically debug AVA run on the command-line.
 From the Command Palette (F1or command + shift + p/ control + shift + p), run Debug: Create JavaScript Debug Terminal Run npx ava in the terminal  Creating a launch configuration Alternatively you can create a launch configuration, which makes it easier to debug individual test files.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
